It takes more than guns to kill a man.
Matewan is a drama, history film directed by John Sayles.
Filmed in the coal country of West Virginia, "Matewan" celebrates
labor organizing in the context of a 1920s work stoppage.
Union organizer, Joe Kenehan, a scab named "Few Clothes" Johnson and a sympathetic mayor and police chief heroically fight the power represented by a coal company and
Matewan's vested interests so that justice and workers' rights need not take a back seat to squalid working conditions, exploitation and the bottom line.
Joe Kenehan, played by Chris Cooper.
'Few Clothes' Johnson, played by James Earl Jones.
Elma Radnor, played by Mary McDonnell.
Danny Radnor, played by Will Oldham.
Police Chief Sid Hatfield, played by David Strathairn.
Sephus Purcell, played by Ken Jenkins.
Matewan () is a 1987 American independent drama film written and directed by John Sayles, and starring Chris Cooper (in his film debut),
James Earl Jones, Mary McDonnell and Will Oldham, with David Strathairn, Kevin Tighe and Gordon Clapp in supporting roles.
The film dramatizes the events of the Battle of Matewan, a coal miners' strike
in 1920 in Matewan, a small town in the hills of West Virginia.
Matewan was a critical success but a box office flop, grossing
under $2 million on an estimated $4 million budget.
The film received a nomination for the Academy Award for Best
Cinematography, and received a Criterion Collection re-release in 2019.
The film explores themes of traitor, based on true
story, west virginia, gun battle, racism.
The tone is emotional.